Yatin Kathuria

Software Developer

Full Stack Web Developer with a proven around **3 years** of experience as a web developer with the working knowledge of **MERN/MVRN Stack**. I am passionate and curious to explore the new technologies and looking forward to adding **AWS** and **Next.js** to my skill set.

yatinkathuria74@gmail.com

Delhi. India

in linkedin.com/in/yatin-kathuria-1b1327174

+91 7011913515

👿 leetcode.com/Yatin-kathuria/

github.com/Yatin-kathuria

WORK EXPERIENCE

SDE-1

Netomi(via Thinkify Labs)

04/2022 - Present

Bangalore, India

Work in Netomi as SDE-1 Frontend via Thinkify Labs. Netomi is the interface for the next generation of customer and company relationships.

- Working in the platform team as a frontend developer, currently building an in-house CHAT BOT (NETOMI WEB WIDGET) as a B2C product. Live Link: https://help.id.me.
- Integrated notification service, which will help the user to get to know if a new message pops up in CHAT BOT.
- Revamp whole CHATBOT dashboard section from scratch in Vue.js.
- · Add animation in the CHATBOT to make it more user interactive.
- Following Agile Methodology for completing the task on time.

Software Developer

Misemind Technologies Pvt Ltd

02/2021 - 04/2022

Delhi, New Delhi

Work in Dell via Misemind Technologies.

- Redesign the Frontend of the project pipeline builder with React.js,
 Redux and Material UI.
- · Create RESTful API's with Node.js and express.js .
- · Integrate Gitlab oAuth in frontend Side.
- Write a test case of the React components.
- Technologies: React, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Redux, GraphQl, Typescript, Material UI, Jest, Enzyme, Git, Jira.

Associate

Samsung Electronics

02/2020 - 09/2020

Noida, Uttar Pradesh

- Work on an in-house employee management system which will help them to manage employees' information.
- · Creating the UI components in React.js.
- Writing the test cases of the React components.

EDUCATION

Computer Science Engineering

Guru Nanak Dev Institute of Technology

04/2016 - 06/2019 Delhi, India

SKILLS



ACHIEVEMENTS

Rank 5 in IPU LEET (2019)

Rank 13 in SLIET (2019)

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Instagram Clone (12/2020 - 04/2021)

- It's a Full Stack project, With all the possible functionality of the Instagram (https://instagram-clone24.herokuapp.com/signin).
- o Backend: Node.js, Express.js, Nodemailer, JWT etc.
- o Frontend :- React, Redux, Context Api, Material UI etc.
- Database:- MongoDb Atlas.

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTION

The Algorithms (11/2021 - Present) 🕝

Open Source resource for learning Data Structures & Algorithms and their implementation in any Programming Language

OTHER PROFILES

Leetcode 🛂

https://leetcode.com/Yatin-kathuria/

HackerRank 🔀

https://www.hackerrank.com/yatinkathuria74

LANGUAGES

English

Professional Working Proficiency

Hind

Full Professional Proficiency